Guide to the Dan Kirsch papers, 1975-2004
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Dan Kirsch papers 1975-2004
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Kirsch, Dan
19.1 linear feet Extent: 10,840 Items
Activist, community organizer, and theater director. Executive director of Charlotte's Lesbian and Gay Community Center. He also founded One Voice, a gay, lesbian and gay-affirmative chorus in Charlotte, NC, and OutCharlotte, an annual cultural festival that celebrated LGBT culture through theater, dance, music, visual art, film and video. Collection documents the activities of Dan Kirsch and his work with various North Carolina gay and lesbian organizations. Organizations represented in the collection include One Voice, the N.C. Lesbian and Gay Pride Board, PELAG, Time Out Youth, OutCharlotte, NC Pride, and The Lesbian and Gay Community Center of Charlotte.
RL.00784
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Dan Kirsch papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2005, 2007, and 2009.
Biographical Note
Activist, community organizer, and theater director. Executive director of Charlotte's Lesbian and Gay Community Center. He also founded One Voice, a gay, lesbian and gay-affirmative chorus in Charlotte, NC, and OutCharlotte, an annual cultural festival that celebrated LGBT culture through theater, dance, music, visual art, film and video.
Collection Overview
Accession (2005-0037) (21 boxes) documents the activities of N.C. gay and lesbian organizations. Includes correspondence, newsletters, programs, flyers, and organizational material from One Voice; organizational material, correspondence, programs, invitations, minutes, registration records, financial records (bulk 1994) from Music & Message, the Gala Choruses Leadership Conference (Sept. 2-4, 1994 in Charlotte); correspondence, newsletters, clippings, financial records (1993-1996), minutes, and administrative records for the N.C. Lesbian and Gay Pride Board; fund raising material for the AIDS fund raiser Heart Strings (June 15, 1992), and Pelag benefit Our Family Celebration (Oct. 12, 1991); and files, promotional materials, newsletters, clippings, minutes, and financial records about a N.C. Lesbian and Gay Pride event, 1994. Also included are posters, t-shirts, 14 VHS video tapes, 1 CD-Rom, 50 photographs, and 25 slides.
Accession (2007-0079) (1600 items; 3 lin. ft.; dated 1991-2002) contains organization files and correspondence for Time Out Youth, an organization for lesbian, gay, and bisexual youth; financial and organizational files for OutCharlotte (1995-1998); NC Pride files; conference materials; and clippings from local publications including the Charlotte Observer, Creative Loafing, and The Leader. Also included are 2 CD-Rs containing audio clips of interviews, 15 Hi8 video cassettes, 9 VHS tapes, 4 audio cassettes, and photographs. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Accession (2009-0173) (2500 items; 3.6 lin. ft.; dated 1999-2004) includes materials from the planning and construction of The Lesbian and Gay Community Center in Charlotte, NC. Also includes The Center program files, administrative materials, board meeting minutes, publicity, and volunteer information.
Subject Headings
Kirsch, Dan; OutCharlotte; Time Out Youth; Gay communities -- North Carolina; Charlotte (N.C.); The Lesbian and Gay Community Center (Charlotte, N.C.); Photographs; Videocassettes; Audiocassettes; CD-Rs; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
Contents of Collection
- Accession (2005-0037), (21 Boxes)
  The 2005 accession documents the activities of N.C. gay and lesbian organizations. Includes correspondence, newsletters, programs, flyers, and organizational material from One Voice; organizational material, correspondence, programs, invitations, minutes, registration records, financial records (bulk 1994) from Music & Message, the Gala Choruses Leadership Conference (Sept. 2-4, 1994 in Charlotte); correspondence, newsletters, clippings, financial records (1993-1996), minutes, and administrative records for the N.C. Lesbian and Gay Pride Board; fund raising material for the AIDS fund raiser Heart Strings (June 15, 1992), and Pelag benefit Our Family Celebration (Oct. 12, 1991); and files, promotional materials, newsletters, clippings, minutes, and financial records about a N.C. Lesbian and Gay Pride event, 1994. Also included are posters, t-shirts, 14 VHS video tapes, 1 CD-Rom, 50 photographs, and 25 slides.
  - One Voice membership, financial records, correspondence, and programs (Box 1)
  - One Voice records (Box 2)
  - GALA records (Box 2)
  - One Voice records, advertisements, and printed material (Box 3)
  - One Voice records, programs, and printed material (Box 4)
  - NC Pride records (Box 5)
  - GALA handbook (Box 5)
  - NC Pride files and printed material (Box 6)
  - NC Pride files, records and printed material (Box 7)
  - NC Pride files and photographs (Box 8)
  - NC Pride files, records and printed material (Box 9)
  - NC Pride files, political and support group files, Heartstrings script, printed material (Box 10)
  - Heartstrings and Our Family Celebration papers (Box 11)
  - GALA files (Box 12)
  - Music & Message files (Box 12)
  - GALA and workshop files (Box 13)
  - GALA, workshop, and conference files (Box 14)
  - GALA files (Box 15)
  - GALA conference files (Box 16)
  - NC Pride files (Box 17)
  - NC Pride files and related materials, (2 buttons; 3 drink insulators) (Box 18)
  - One Voice files (Box 19)
  - Videocassettes, (9 items) (Box 19)
  - Compact disc (Box 19)
  - T-shirts, (3 items) (Box 20)
  - Painting (Box 20)
  - Gay Pride files, 1994 (Box 21)
  - Videocassettes, (5 items) (Box 21)
- Accession (2007-0079), (5 Boxes)
  The 2007 addition (dated 1991-2002) contains organization files and correspondence for Time Out Youth, an organization for lesbian, gay, and bisexual youth; financial and organizational files for OutCharlotte (1995-1998); NC Pride files; conference materials; and clippings from local publications including the Charlotte Observer, Creative Loafing, and The Leader. Also included are 2 CD-Rs containing audio clips of interviews, 15 Hi8 video cassettes, 9 VHS tapes, 4 audio cassettes, and photographs.
  - OutCharlotte files, 1995-1997 (Box 22)
    Financial, workshop, board and committee files
  - OutCharlotte files, 1997-1998 (Box 23)
    Financial, workshop, strategic plans, board and committee files
  - Photographs (Box 24)
  - Time Out Youth files (Box 24)
  - Clippings (Box 24)
  - Videocassettes, (9 VHS tapes; 15 Hi8 tapes) (Box 25)
  - Audiocassettes, (4 items) (Box 25)
  - CD-Rs, (2 items) (Box 25)
  - Clippings (Box 26)
  - The Bear Men of Charlotte calendar, 1992 (Box 26)
- Accession (2009-0173), (6 boxes)
  Addition (2009-0173) (2500 items; 3.6 lin. ft.; dated 1998-2004) includes materials from the planning and construction of The Lesbian and Gay Community Center in Charlotte, NC. Also includes The Center program files, administrative materials, board meeting minutes, publicity, and volunteer information.
  - Center Leadership Trust (Box 27)
  - Center Leadership Sustainers (Box 27)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and photographs, 2003-2004 (Box 27)
  - Volunteers (Box 27)
  - Originals/forms (Box 27)
  - Center calendars of events, 2003 (Box 27)
  - Miscellaneous, 2001-2002 (2 folders) (Box 27)
    Includes correspondence, city maps, essays and articles, sign-up sheets, photographs, event planning materials, and drafts from The Center.
  - Miscellaneous, 2002 (Box 28)
    Includes contact and member lists, drafts of press releases, and correspondence.
  - Center publications and newsletters, 2002 (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous administration materials: job duties, internal policies, board applications (Box 28)
  - Donor research, 1998-2003 (Box 28)
  - Community Center Kickoff, 2000-2001 (2 folders) (Box 28)
  - Richard Florida event (UNC Charlotte), 2003 (Box 28)
  - National Gay and Lesbian Funding Partnership, 2004 (Box 28)
  - Other organization publications and brochures, 2003-2004 (Box 28)
  - Front and Center training packet (Box 28)
  - Tenant meeting originals, 2003-2004 (Box 28)
  - Board files, 2002 (3 folders) (Box 28)
  - Board files, 2003 (5 folders) (Box 28)
  - Board files, 2004 (Box 29)
  - Press releases, 2002 (Box 29)
  - Programs and events (Box 29)
  - Center film series, 2003 (Box 29)
  - Center art commission from John W. Love Jr. and Willie Little (Box 29)
  - ReachOut/Creative Development and Support, 2001-2002 (Box 29)
  - Artists/Gallery (Box 29)
  - Faith traditions, 2003 (Box 29)
  - Leadership Training Day, 2002 (Box 29)
  - Building 1401 central renovation (Box 29)
  - Center construction, 2002 (Box 30)
  - Facilities, 2002 (Box 30)
  - Community center space (Box 30)
  - Community Center Planning Committee, 1998-2002 (5 folders) (Box 30)
  - Community Center Study/Planning Committee, 1999-2001 (Box 31)
  - Project transition to Center, 2002 (Box 31)
  - Center Leadership Trust (Box 31)
  - City Council/County Commissioners, 2003 (Box 31)
  - Tenant correspondence, 2002 (Box 31)
- Oversize, (1 folder)
  - Miscellaneous (Opaperfolder 1)